去火星没什么事是敢打包票的
Nothing can be taken for granted when you get to Mars.
有太多我们不知道的事儿了
There's a lot of things we just don't know.
太空总会给我们带来未知与挑战
Space always has a way of throwing us curveballs and surprising us.
在得到准确的着陆数据之前
I mean, until we get the data that says we're on the ground safely
我都会一直担心我们有失败的可能
I'm gonna be worried that we're not gonna make it.
毅力号的进入大气、下降与着陆
PERSEVERANCE'S ENTRY, DESCENT AND LANDING
进入大气、下降和着陆一般统称为“恐怖七分钟”
Entry, Descent and Landing is often referred to as the seven minutes of terror.
因为从大气外进入大气 一直到安稳着陆大约要花七分钟
Because it takes about seven minutes to get from the top of the atmosphere of Mars to the ground safely.
在这个阶段航天器要全靠自己运作
The spacecraft has to do all of this by itself.
要想让毅力号安全着陆 一切动作都要准确执行
There are many things that have to go right to get Perseverance onto the ground safely.
这次任务意义很大 这是火星采样返回任务接力的第一棒
There's a lot counting on this. This is the first leg of our sample return relay race.
有相当多的工作要做
There's a lot of work on the line.
在进入大气前七分钟
Starting about ten minutes before atmospheric entry,
火星车将和一直伴随它的巡航段分离
we get rid of really the spacecraft part of the rover that's been supporting us.
然后以每小时12000-13000英里(20000km/h左右)的速度扎入火星大气
We come screaming into the Martian atmosphere at twelve to thirteen thousand miles per hour.
头部的防热大底将通过与大气摩擦 把初始能量消耗掉
And the heat shield is what dissipates all that initial energy through friction.
飞船会继续靠自己在大气中飞行
The vehicle will continue actually flying itself through the atmosphere.
有点像是从太空来的航天器变成了一个能自我导航的“航空器”
It's sort of like a transforming vehicle that went from spacecraft
and now it's kind of like an aircraft actively guiding itself.
当速度减少到足够慢的时候 它将部署降落伞
When we're going slow enough we deploy a parachute.
它是人类送到其他星球上的最大的超音速降落伞
It's the biggest supersonic parachute we've ever sent to another planet.
对于给火星车减速起到关键作用
It's critical for slowing down the vehicle.
毅力号的进入大气、下降和着陆过程很大程度上借鉴了好奇号的经验
Perseverance's Entry, Descent and Landing borrows heavily from that of Curiosity.
但从火星车上讲 毅力号比好奇号更大 携带设备也有所不同
But fundamentally, Perseverance is a different rover She's bigger, she has different instruments.
我们给它加装了很多智能设备
We've added a lot of smarts on the inside to make it more capable
可以自行处理我们给提供的着陆点信息
so that it can deal with the landing site that we've given it.
科学团队选择的着陆点Jezero陨石坑是一个古老的湖床
The science team identified Jezero Crater as basically an ancient lakebed.
是探寻远古微生物踪迹的最理想的位置
And one of the most promising places to look for evidence of ancient microbial life
也方便未来采样并返回地球的任务
and to collect samples for future return to Earth.
但问题是这地方着陆太危险了
The problem is it's a much more hazardous place to land.
Jezero陨石坑到处都写着“危险”二字
When you look at Jezero, all you see is danger.
我们将如何降落在一个曾认为对着陆来说非常不安全的地方呢？
How do we go to a site that we never thought was safe enough to go to before?
回到刚刚说的防热大底 我们经历了进入大气阶段 已经不需要它了
So the heat shield, which has protected us all the way through entry, is no longer necessary.
我们需要把它抛掉 才能真真切切看到地面
We need to get that off so we can actually see the ground.
而我们有很多种方法来观察地面
And we can see the ground in a couple of different ways.
毅力号将是第一个试用地形关联导航技术的任务
Perseverance will be the first mission to use Terrain Relative Navigation.
当它带着降落伞慢慢下降时
So while it's descending on the parachute,
它会开始给火星表面拍照 并依据所见内容判断前往哪里
it will actually be taking images of the surface of Mars and determining where to go based on what it sees.
就好像你睁着眼睛在着陆一样
This is finally like landing with your eyes open.
有了这个技术 毅力号将能够降落在比以往好奇号和其他火星任务中
Having this new technology really allows Perseverance to land in much more challenging terrain
更加具有挑战的地形中
than Curiosity or any previous Mars mission could.
在大量巨石、陨石坑和断崖之间 它们对于火星车来说都是很危险的
Amongst the rocks and the craters and the cliffs - these things are hazardous to the rover
但对于科学家来说却是最令人感兴趣的
but these are the things that are interesting to the scientists.
当毅力号判断出它的位置后
Once Perseverance has figured out where she is,
将和后盖与降落伞分离
we jettison the backshell and the parachute,
点燃火箭发动机
and light up our rockets.
这些火箭发动机将把毅力号带到附近的安全着陆点
Those rockets help us steer to a safe landing spot that's nearby.
下降级会一路降到火星表面20米高
That descent stage takes us all the way down to about twenty meters off the ground.
然后天空起重机开始下放火星车
That's when we start the skycrane maneuver.
当火星车着陆后
Once the rover has hit the ground,
下降级会切断与火星车之间的缆绳 然后飞到安全距离外
the descent stage will cut loose from the rover and fly away to a safe distance.
而活过“恐怖七分钟”只是毅力号的开始
Surviving that seven minutes is really just the beginning for Perseverance.
它的使命——火星采样任务的第一步、寻找火星过去存在生命的证据
It's job, right, being the first leg of sample return to go look for those signs of past life on Mars
这一切都要等它安全着陆后才能开始
- all that can't start until we get Perseverance safely to the ground.
之后 真正的任务才正式开始
And then, that's when the real mission begins.
直播将于太平洋时间上午11:15开始
2021年2月18日 着陆火星